[footsteps]
[MAN 06A panting]
[MAN 06A continues panting]
[snarling]
[MAN 06A panting]
[chuckles]
It's a manmade wonder.
I'm doing well. And you?
I've seen a lot,
but nothing this impressive.
Tch.
[ENDERS] Why are there
so many dregs boarding?
They're sullying this majestic
vessel's maiden voyage.
[FRED] They're passengers,
the same as you, sir.
The passenger cabins
have different classes.
And a decent number of them
are priced quite moderately
I'm saying this ship is only fit
to be boarded by noblemen.
Gaze upon it. I dare you
to tell me otherwise.
[ENDERS]
She's the Noahtic.
A ship truly worthy of
taking on the name "Noah."
Be frank.
Do you think a commoner
would be selected
to construct the Ark,
saving all of humankind?
Uh.
[ENDERS] Noah was chosen by God!
He obviously was a nobleman,
no different than me!
[ENDERS]
Look around you.
Notice the multitudes of God's
chosen eager to venture forth.
Now, picture this.
Say by chance,
a great flood were to hit
London while we were at sea.
There'd be no substantial loss.
Don't you agree?
The only ones left
on this island
would be the lowest of the low.
If only they were
swallowed up by the waves,
society'd have a chance.
[LADY 06A gasps] Isn't that
Lord Enders over there?
Of course, a man of his standing
would book passage
on the Noahtic.
[LADY 06C] It is such an honour
to make your acquaintance!
What a relief, knowing refined
creatures will be aboard.
[LADY 06A] Naturally,
we couldn't resist the urge
to watch a once in
a lifetime performance!
[LADY 06B] The first ballet
performed at sea!
Missing such a monumental
event is unthinkable!
[ENDERS laughs]
What lovely minds to
match your lovely faces.
Onward. Let's take
our rightful place.
After all, the arc was built for
carrying noble blood like ours.
[LADY 06A]
You lead the way, Lord Enders!
I'm pleased to report
that the target
has boarded at
the scheduled time.
[WILLIAM] Well, let's
get this show started.
I often reflect on the
inequity within this country.
It has long
occupied my thoughts.
And we're all keenly
aware of the cause:
The broken class system, which
benefits a wealthy minority,
whilst depriving everyone else.
The temple must
come crashing down.
We're in agreement.
But who do we target
and how do we go about it?
[WILLIAM] We can't change
the system overnight.
However, something is achievable
in the immediate future.
We can turn London into
a city overrun with crime,
plunging it into
the depths of Hell.
[BOTH gasp]
[ALBERT chuckles]
Intriguing, but I need
to hear more details.
For starters, how does this help
advance our objective of
improving life in this country?
[WILLIAM] Crime is not
our ultimate objective;
it's a means to
an end. That's all.
As I stated, we cannot
change the system
with a single decisive action.
But with a well-placed stab,
we could change
the minds of men.
How so?
Human beings have a
wide range of emotions
and are quite often
willing to act upon them.
But there's one event
that drives them
to act above all else.
It's called death.
[BOTH grunt]
I concur with you. Death,
above all else, is instrumental.
Look, if me dying's gonna help
advance your plan in any way,
well then, I'm your man.
Same goes for you, right?
[FRED]
Mm.
[WILLIAM]
I guaranteed Londoners a show.
And I have many deaths and
misdeeds tailor made for them.
[WOMAN 06A gasps]
[WILLIAM]
In short...
[AUDIENCE shrieks]
[WILLIAM] ...crime will
transform the city into a stage.
And its citizens shall become
the audience, bearing witness.
[ALBERT] You propose turning the
whole of London into a theatre?
[WILLIAM]
Not only that,
I've also chosen the
theme for our performances:
Exposing the ills of
our society through murder.
We'll work uncredited,
Choreographing the deaths
and presenting them
in a dramatic fashion.
The people of this country need
an explosive display
to open their eyes.
[MORAN] And I suspect we're the
ones pulling the trigger.
Should prove to be interesting.
[WILLIAM chuckles]
[WILLIAM]
Very soon
the time will come
for the curtain to rise.
Depending on the success
of our forthcoming show,
it could mark a
significant step towards
the world we've
been striving for.
But before that,
I'll present our
first illustrious star.
[WILLIAM] A recognizable name,
Count Blitz Enders.
[ENDERS]
Step aside.
[THOMAS MICHAELSON grunts]
Hey!
Who're you to board
ahead of everyone else?
We were here first!
Get to the back of the line!
Do you have any idea
who you have the
privilege of addressing?
[THOMAS MICHAELSON]
Huh?
Lines were made for swine
like you, not lords and ladies.
[THOMAS MICHAELSON]
What did you call me?
[MORAN] Accept my
sincerest apologies, sir.
Step right this way
if you would please.
[ENDERS scoffs] It won't do any
good arguing with these people.
If they choose to board
the boat like cattle,
they ought to be
placed down in the hold
like they livestock they are.
Get back here!
[STEWARD 06A]
The captain would like to extend
a warm welcome
to all passengers.
[CAPTAIN 06A] The Noahtic is now
beginning its pleasure cruise
towards our destination
of Amsterdam.
In addition, tomorrow,
the world's first shipborne
ballet will be performed.
We hope you all enjoy the show,
as well as the remainder
of your voyage.
[CROWD chatters]
And how is our
"event" coming along?
[WILLIAM chuckles]
Impatient as always, I see.
The curtain will rise
once everyone's in place.
[ALBERT]
Pity. Very well.
While I eagerly await
the start of the show,
I'll have to find some
way to entertain myself.
[ENDERS]
Preposterous!
You don't have a
reservation under my name?!
That's simply impossible!
I am terribly sorry,
but unfortunately, there was a
slight mix-up with your table.
What do you mean a mix-up?
However, if you'd like,
I could have a table prepared
for you at our restaurant
located on the lower deck.
So, in other words,
you're saying I'm fit
to dine with the livestock
while they stuff their gullets
in some mess hall below?
Is that it?!
I would never
insinuate that, sir.
I belong to the
upper class, which means
peasants don't even deserve
the honor of watching me eat!
Are we clear?
[WAITER 06A]
Y-Yes, sir.
If you'll wait just one moment,
I'll have this sorted out.
We'll find you seating at once.
- -[splash]
- -[CHILD 6A gasps]
[ENDERS growls]
[MOTHER 06A]
I'm so sorry, Lord Enders!
[ENDERS groans]
If we so happen to
cross paths again,
I swear, I'll murder you.
[CHILD 06A yelps, cries]
[CHILD 06A]
Mummy!
Oh! What's the matter, honey?
I can't think of any
reason why commoners
would be this close
to a restaurant
solely for first class.
Apparently, the entire vessel
is crawling with
all manner of vermin.
[WILLIAM]
That was unfortunate.
Might I offer you this, sir?
Oh. Thank you kindly.
[WILLIAM] My name is Moriarty.
William James Moriarty.
Moriarty, huh?
I've heard the name before.
You served in the army?
[WILLIAM] You're thinking
of my older brother, Albert.
He's also on board.
I'll have to
introduce you later.
[WAITER 06A] Lord Enders, we
have a table prepared for you.
This way.
Right. Till next time.
I can't wait to see
what you mess up next.
What sort of ship are
you running here?!
I get 'em riled
up enough for you?
[MORAN]
Yes. Well played.
I trust you'll continue to
aggravate the lord
for the remainder of our time
at sea, Mister Michaelson.
Those were the terms
of the agreement
and I ain't contesting 'em.
But I just got one question.
Why go through all the trouble
of pesterin' some ponce?
Huh?
It's not your place to inquire.
That was also part of
our agreement, remember?
[THOMAS MICHAELSON grunts]
Long as I'm paid
what we agreed on,
you won't get
no quarrel from me.
[WILLIAM]
His name's Thomas Michaelson.
A habitual burglar
who's committed
a litany of crimes,
including rape and even
murder when it suited him.
[WILLIAM]
We will take his depraved life
and make good use of it.
[NOBLEMAN 06A] Lord Moriarty,
what a lovely surprise.
Didn't imagine
I'd be running into you,
and here, of all places.
If this were merely
a cruise, I confess,
I would have
very little interest.
But I heard a magnificent
spectacle was taking place.
Might you be referring to the
world's first shipborne ballet?
[ALBERT chuckles]
[NOBLEMAN 06A]
Why that's the very reason
I bought a ticket myself.
[ALBERT]
You don't say.
As a ballet aficionado, I'm sure
it was impossible to resist.
You have deduced correctly.
I'll admit, the moment
I stepped foot on the ship,
I haven't been able to stop
thinking about the performance.
[ALBERT] Yes. I as well. I'm
sure whatever they have prepared
will leave us breathless.
[ENDERS growls]
[knocking]
[FRED] Blitz Enders.
I have a telegram for you, sir.
[ENDERS]
Hm?
[WILLIAM]
Should be any moment now
I expect our lead will be
receiving some unfortunate news.
[grunts]
[LADY 06D]
Amazing!
How did you know that
gentleman was in the military?
[LADY 06E] Surely, he mentioned
it to you beforehand!
[LADY 06F]
Hmm... What about that man?
Can you guess his profession?
[HOLMES]
Hmm.
Yeah, I got it.
You barely looked!
[LADY 06E]
If you guess correctly,
that'll be ten times in a row!
Beg your pardon, sir.
It seems you've become
an unwilling participant
in our bet.
A bet? Really?
[LADY 06F]
Yes.
It simply entails us standing
here, people watching,
while he takes a guess
as to their occupations.
Go on and tell us quickly!
What does that
gentleman do for a living?
[HOLMES] Regarding
the man's line of work,
it's rather elementary.
He's a mathematician.
It's rather elementary.
[LADY 06E]
Now explain it step-by-step.
[LADY 06F]
Yes! Please, indulge us!
[HOLMES]
First,
there's no denying it's
a hell of a spiral staircase.
I can see why you
were admiring it.
Ah. Which element, though?
What makes you so sure
I'm a mathematician?
Hmm? It's simple.
Whilst I was observing,
I noticed how long
you stood in place,
distance, and the
angle you chose.
I'll continue.
Truth can be found
through simple deductions
based on knowledge and behavior.
Despite clearly being
absorbed in thought
while walking across the lounge,
your concentration was broken
once you reached the stairs.
Dare I say,
almost as if the sight had
caused your mind
to come to momentary halt
and all other
matters dissipated.
There's no denying the staircase
is beautifully adorned
and worth admiring.
But where was your attention?
You didn't step closer to
appreciate the
intricate ornamentation.
Instead, you took
a step backwards,
allowing you to observe
the staircase as a whole.
And what profession
matches this behavior?
An appreciation for
the "construction"
and not "cosmetic beauty"?
An architect?
Or a physicist, perhaps?
On the contrary...
His piercing gaze was
not directed at the column
because his interest
wasn't in the manner
in which the stairs
were supported.
So, the question becomes
what was he looking at that
caused him to step backwards?
He wanted the grand scope.
To seek confirmation.
The curve of the staircase
and whether or not
it adhered to
a certain principle:
The divine proportion.
By which I mean
the golden ratio.
You're correct.
What a keen observer you are.
Whilst the logic of your
argument was a trifle forced,
I am a professor. I teach
mathematics at university.
Then you mean...
That makes ten in a row!
Now then, it would be remiss
of me not to return the favour.
Uh.
[WILLIAM]
Where to start?
You play the strings,
violin specifically,
but you're not
a professional musician.
Additionally, you're adept
in physical activities,
such as boxing.
You have an avid interest in
scientific experiments and...
[WILLIAM sniffs]
Do I detect the slightest hint
of a chemical dependency?
[HOLMES grunts]
Even though you give
me the impression
of being an Oxbridge
educated man,
I find your dialect
to be more in the vein
of the working class.
As for the why,
no doubt it's because you
take pride in your ancestry,
specifically,
your mother's side.
Well?
How'd you ever guess?
I didn't.
Everything I said was a fact.
[laughs] What an
intriguing chap!
Do you think so?
Come! There are more
people on the upper deck.
Still not sated?
[LADY 06E]
Hardly, we're going to have to
make you keep going
until you make a mistake!
I'm at your mercy.
Oh, professor. See you around.
[LADY 06D]
It never gets old.
Anything wrong?
No.
He shouldn't pose any
great hindrance to our plan.
And you?
Everything's on schedule.
The target's on
the verge of breaking.
Good. Continue
chipping away at him.
At this rate, it shouldn't
take much longer.
His endurance is all
but depleted.
[LADY 06A] He looks grim.
What could be troubling him?
[LADY 06C]
From what I understand,
he's had a streak of bad luck.
More than that.
He received a telegram
saying his cottage burnt down
and there was an accident
at his colliery.
I can't imagine the poor man
would want any company.
Probably best to leave him be.
You're right.
[ENDERS] It doesn't make sense.
Why is this happening?
Ever since I've boarded,
I've met with misfortune
as though there's
some conspiracy
to ruin and humiliate me!
Damn it all!
I can't take much more!
What I wouldn't give for the
comfort of my hunting grounds!
No.
Wait. Why should they
be limited to the woods?
[ENDERS]
This is, after all, Noah's Ark.
And the nobility
are the only passengers
which could be considered human.
There is certainly no shortage
of dumb beasts aboard
I can select from to be my prey.
[chuckles]
[THOMAS MICHAELSON] You're
absolutely sure about this?
[ENDERS]
While there's nothing I can do
to take back the truly
dreadful things I said
while we were boarding,
I will do my utmost
to apologize.
Hah! You aristocrats know
how to correct a mistake.
[ENDERS]
Check the inner stateroom.
[THOMAS MICHAELSON]
They pull out all the stops
for first-class
cabins, don't they?
[gasps] Lord have mercy!
Which of you to start with?
It's so hard to choose.
[THOMAS MICHAELSON] This is all
too perfect.
I'll pretend
I'm good and soused,
make him throw a fit
and apologize again.
Won't take long to
wheedle all the spirits
out of this rich
twit's liquor cabinet.
[THOMAS MICHAELSON]
Between you and me,
I always can pick
a winner. Heh, heh.
This should do.
I can any have
any bottle I want?
Yes,
on one condition:
If you somehow survive!
- -[thud]
- -[THOMAS MICHAELSON groans]
You're mad!
[ENDERS cackles]
There really is no difference
between you and a swine!
Even your pleas before death
sound like a squealing animal's!
[THOMAS MICHAELSON]
No! Don't!
- -[ENDERS grunts]
- -[THOMAS MICHAELSON screams]
What a fine evening
this has been.
There really is a
different zest to killing
using your own hands.
A gun can be so
clinical and unfeeling.
I'll have to implement it into
my hunting regime.
[MORAN]
Pardon,
but that special cut of meat
you ordered is ready, sir.
Also, the room has been
left unlocked for you.
So whenever you feel inclined...
Thank you kindly.
[ENDERS grunts, chuckles]
[knocking]
[WILLIAM]
Lord Enders?
[gasps]
[WILLIAM] It's Moriarty.
Forgive me, but one of
the ladies informed me
that she heard a shout
coming from your room.
Are you not feeling well?
I was terribly concerned
and wanted to check on you.
[ENDERS]
Not Moriarty!
This is bad! What do I do?
If he finds the carcass,
I'm finished!
[WILLIAM grunts]
The door's opened.
I'm letting myself in.
[ENDERS] But I distinctly
remember locking it behind me!
[WILLIAM]
Lord Enders? Are you in here?
[ENDERS] Wait. I'm just--
Just a moment!
Oh.
[ENDERS gasping]
[WILLIAM] I must say...
this is quite serious.
[HOLMES] Next time
on Moriarty the Patriot  .
"The Noahtic Act Two."